arr = [
    {
        question : "Which of these is true?",
        option : [
            "Wildlife conservation is the same as wildlife preservation",
            "Wildlife conservation is the same as wildlife ecology",
            "Wildlife conservation is the same as environment ",
            "none of these"
        ],
        correct : "none of these"
    },
    {
        question : "Good climate is a ",
        option : [
            "chemical factor",
            "demographic factor",
            "push factor",
            "pull factor"
        ],
        correct : "pull factor"
    },
    {
        question : "The discipline of demography is most closely related to:",
        option : [
            "Phytogeography",
            "Zoogeography",
            "population geography",
            "economic geography"
        ],
        correct : "population geography"
    },
    {
        question : "The systematic approach to geography was developed by",
        option : [
            "Alexander von Humboldt",
            "Karl Ritter",
            "Rene Descartes",
            "Eratosthenes"
        ],
        correct : "Alexander von Humboldt"
    },
    {
        question : "The regional approach to geography was developed by",
        option : [
            "Alexander von Humboldt",
            "Karl Ritter",
            "Rene Descartes",
            "Eratosthenes"
        ],
        correct : "Karl Ritter"
    },
    {
        question : "\"Science of relationships between organism and their environments\" is the definition of:",
        option : [
            "conservation",
            "preservation",
            "environmentalism",
            "ecology"
        ],
        correct : "ecology"
    },
    {
        question : "In the word root for conservation, con stands for",
        option : [
            "together",
            "to keep",
            "house",
            "manage"
        ],
        correct : "together"
    },
    {
        question : "\"allowing some places and some creatures to exist without significant human interference\" is the definition of:",
        option : [
            "conservation",
            "preservation",
            "environmentalism",
            "ecology"
        ],
        correct : "preservation"
    },
    {
        question : "The geographical discipline of climatology is most closely related to:",
        option : [
            "geology",
            "meteorology",
            "hydrology",
            "pedology"
        ],
        correct : "meteorology"
    },
    {
        question : "The movement of individuals away from their place of birth or hatching or seed production into a new habitat or area to survive and reproduce is called",
        option : [
            "translocation",
            "migration",
            "dispersal",
            "drifting"
        ],
        correct : "dispersal"
    },
    {
        question : "Within a depositional basin, strata are laterally continuous in all directions till the edge of the basin. This is known as",
        option : [
            "Principle of superposition",
            "Principle of original horizontally",
            "Principle of lateral continuity",
            "Principle of inclusions"
        ],
        correct : "Principle of lateral continuity"
    },
    {
        question : "Mount Vesuvius is an example of",
        option : [
            "Shield volcano",
            "composite volcano",
            "caldera",
            "flood basalt province"
        ],
        correct : "composite volcano"
    },
    {
        question : "The main source of magma is",
        option : [
            "crust",
            "mantle",
            "outer core",
            "inner core"
        ],
        correct : "mantle"
    },
    {
        question : "Which of these is true about P waves?",
        option : [
            "They are longitudinal in nature",
            "they are transverse in nature",
            "they cannot move through gases",
            "they cannot move through liquids"
        ],
        correct : "They are longitudinal in nature"
    },
    {
        question : "Deccan traps are an example of",
        option : [
            "shield volcano",
            "stratovolcano",
            "caldera",
            "flood basalt province"
        ],
        correct : "flood basalt province"
    },
    {
        question : "Krakatoa eruption resulted in the formation of",
        option : [
            "shield volcano",
            "stratovolcano",
            "caldera",
            "flood basalt province"
        ],
        correct : "caldera"
    },
    {
        question : "Which of these is a gas giant?",
        option : [
            "mercury",
            "venus",
            "mars",
            "saturn"
        ],
        correct : "saturn"
    },
    {
        question : "Which of these is an example of direct source of information about of Earth?",
        option : [
            "earthquakes",
            "volcanic eruption",
            "magnetic survey",
            "gravity anomaly"
        ],
        correct : "volcanic eruption"
    },
    {
        question : "Moho discontinuity occurs between",
        option : [
            "crust and mantle",
            "mantle and outer core",
            "outer core and inner core",
            "oceanic crust and continental crust"
        ],
        correct : "crust and mantle"
    },
    {
        question : "Assemblage of fossils are unique to the time that they lived in, and so can be used to age rocks across a wide geographic distribution. This is known as",
        option : [
            "principle of fossil succession",
            "principle of original horizontally",
            "principle of superposition",
            "principle of cross- cutting relationships"
        ],
        correct : "principle of fossil succession"
    },
    {
        question : "\"light cream to salmon pink coloured tectosilicate minerals forming half of the Earth's crust\" is a description of",
        option : [
            "amphiboles",
            "feldspar",
            "mica",
            "olivine"
        ],
        correct : "feldspar"
    },
    {
        question : "\"green or black coloured inocilicates forming 10% of the earth's crust\" is a description of",
        option : [
            "amphiboles",
            "quartz",
            "feldspar",
            "pyroxene"
        ],
        correct : "pyroxene"
    },
    {
        question : "Which of these is correct?",
        option : [
            "intrusive rocks: formed outside crust, often coarse grained",
            "intrusive rocks: formed inside crust, often fine grained",
            "extrusive rocks: formed outside crust, often fine grained",
            "extrusive rocks: formed inside crust, often coarse grained"
        ],
        correct : "extrusive rocks: formed outside crust, often fine grained"
    },
    {
        question : "cryofracturing is an example of",
        option : [
            "chemical weathering",
            "physical weathering",
            "biological weathering",
            "none of these"
        ],
        correct : "physical weathering"
    },
    {
        question : "Mudrock is an example of",
        option : [
            "siliciclastic rock",
            "carbonate rock",
            "evaporite rock",
            "phosphatic rock"
        ],
        correct : "siliciclastic rock"
    },
    {
        question : "\"sheet silicate minerals with pearly, vitreous lustre\" is a description of",
        option : [
            "pyroxene",
            "feldspar",
            "mica",
            "quartz"
        ],
        correct : "mica"
    },
    {
        question : "Sandstone is an example of",
        option : [
            "siliciclastic rock",
            "carbonate rock",
            "evaporite rock",
            "phosphatic rock"
        ],
        correct : "siliciclastic rock"
    },
    {
        question : "Hydrolysis is an example of",
        option : [
            "chemical weathering",
            "physical weathering",
            "biological weathering",
            "none of these"
        ],
        correct : "chemical weathering"
    },
    {
        question : "Which of these is an example of exogenic process?",
        option : [
            "volcanism",
            "earthquake",
            "plate tectonics",
            "deposition"
        ],
        correct : "deposition"
    },
    {
        question : "Thermal stresses lead to",
        option : [
            "chemical weathering",
            "physical weathering",
            "biological weathering",
            "none of these"
        ],
        correct : "physical weathering"
    },
    {
        question : "Surplus seed and sperm banking is an adaptation option to facilitate",
        option : [
            "resistance to climate changes",
            "resilience to climate changes",
            "response to climate changes",
            "none of these"
        ],
        correct : "resilience to climate changes"
    },
    {
        question : "The ISS orbits in which layer?",
        option : [
            "Troposphere",
            "Stratosphere",
            "Mesosphere",
            "Thermosphere"
        ],
        correct : "Thermosphere"
    },
    {
        question : "From the surface of the Earth to upwards, which of these is the correct sequence of atmospheric layers?",
        option : [
            "troposphere, stratosphere, mesosphere, thermosphere, exosphere",
            "troposphere, mesosphere, stratosphere, thermosphere, exosphere",
            "ptroposphere, mesosphere, stratosphere, thermosphere, exosphere",
            "troposphere, exosphere, thermosphere, mesosphere, stratosphere"
        ],
        correct : "troposphere, stratosphere, mesosphere, thermosphere, exosphere"
    },
    {
        question : "Which of these is true about Coriolis force on the Earth?",
        option : [
            "It is maximum at poles and zero at equator",
            "It is zero at poles and maximum at Equator",
            "in the northern hemisphere, it deflects winds towards lefts",
            "in the southern hemisphere, if deflects winds towards right"
        ],
        correct : "It is maximum at poles and zero at equator"
    },
    {
        question : "Most meteors burn in which layer?",
        option : [
            "Troposphere",
            "Stratosphere",
            "Mesosphere",
            "Thermosphere"
        ],
        correct : "Mesosphere"
    },
    {
        question : "Which of these air masses is generally warm and moist?",
        option : [
            "cP",
            "cT",
            "mP",
            "mT"
        ],
        correct : "mT"
    },
    {
        question : "Which of these air masses is generally cold and dry?",
        option : [
            "cP",
            "cT",
            "mP",
            "mT"
        ],
        correct : "cP"
    },
    {
        question : "Aurora borealis occurs in which layer?",
        option : [
            "Troposphere",
            "Stratosphere",
            "Mesosphere",
            "Thermosphere"
        ],
        correct : "Thermosphere"
    },
    {
        question : "Which of these air masses is generally hot and dry?",
        option : [
            "cP",
            "cT",
            "mP",
            "mT"
        ],
        correct : "cT"
    },
    {
        question : "Which of these contains the most water vapour and aerosois?",
        option : [
            "Troposphere",
            "Stratosphere",
            "Mesosphere",
            "Thermosphere"
        ],
        correct : "Troposphere"
    },
    {
        question : "Equal temperature curves are called",
        option : [
            "isopycnal curves",
            "isohaline curves",
            "isotherm curves",
            "isohuovant curves"
        ],
        correct : "isotherm curves"
    },
    {
        question : "\"deep valleys, often cutting across continental shelves and slopes\" is a description of",
        option : [
            "oceanic deep/ trench",
            "mis- oceanic ridge",
            "guyot",
            "submarine canyon"
        ],
        correct : "submarine canyon"
    },
    {
        question : "Continental shelf has a gradient of",
        option : [
            "0- 1 degree",
            "1- 2 degree",
            "2- 5 degree",
            "5- 10 degree"
        ],
        correct : "0- 1 degree"
    },
    {
        question : "Equal salinity curves are called",
        option : [
            "isopycnal curves",
            "isohaline curves",
            "isotherm curves",
            "isohuovant curves"
        ],
        correct : "isohaline curves"
    },
    {
        question : "\"Low islands consisting of coral reefs surrounding a central depression\" is a description of",
        option : [
            "oceanic deep/ trench",
            "mid- oceanic ridge",
            "seamount",
            "atoll"
        ],
        correct : "atoll"
    },
    {
        question : "Equal density curves are called",
        option : [
            "isopycnal curves",
            "isohaline curves",
            "isotherm curves",
            "isohuovant curves"
        ],
        correct : "isopycnal curves"
    },
    {
        question : "Continental slope has a gradient of",
        option : [
            "0- 1 degree",
            "1- 2 degree",
            "2- 5 degree",
            "5- 10 degree"
        ],
        correct : "2- 5 degree"
    },
    {
        question : "\"relatively steep- sided, narrow, deep basins\" is description of",
        option : [
            "oceanic deep/ trench",
            "mid- oceanic ridge",
            "seamount",
            "atoll"
        ],
        correct : "oceanic deep/ trench"
    },
    {
        question : "Which of these is a minor feature of these ocean floor?",
        option : [
            "continental shelf",
            "continental slope",
            "guyot",
            "abyssal plain"
        ],
        correct : "guyot"
    },
    {
        question : "A flat topped sea mount is called",
        option : [
            "trench",
            "plateau",
            "guyot",
            "ridge"
        ],
        correct : "guyot"
    },
    {
        question : "Which of these is the correct sequence of seasons in India?",
        option : [
            "Hot weather season --> retreating monsoon season --> south- west monsoon season --> cold weather season",
            "Hot weather season --> south- west monsoon season --> retreating monsoon season --> cold weather season",
            "hot weather season --> cold weather season --> south- west monsoon season --> retreating monsoon season",
            "hot weather season --> south- west monsoon season --> cold weather season --> retreating monsoon season"
        ],
        correct : "Hot weather season --> south- west monsoon season --> retreating monsoon season --> cold weather season"
    },
    {
        question : "In Koeppen classification, which is steppe precipitation?",
        option : [
            "W",
            "S",
            "f",
            "s"
        ],
        correct : "S"
    },
    {
        question : "In Koeppen classification, which id polar frost temperature?",
        option : [
            "c",
            "d",
            "F",
            "T"
        ],
        correct : "F"
    },
    {
        question : "In Koeppen classification, which is hot summer temperature?",
        option : [
            "h",
            "k",
            "a",
            "b"
        ],
        correct : "a"
    },
    {
        question : "Which of these are factors determining the climate of India?",
        option : [
            "the latitudinal extent",
            "the Himalayas forming a climatic divide",
            "distribution of land and water",
            "all of these"
        ],
        correct : "all of these"
    },
    {
        question : "Winter rains are common in",
        option : [
            "western coastal region of India",
            "Eastern coastal region of India",
            "Interiors of peninsular India",
            "Northern plains of India"
        ],
        correct : "Eastern coastal region of India"
    },
    {
        question : "Which of these are geological regions of India?",
        option : [
            "mountains",
            "the peninsular block",
            "the indo- ganga- brahmaputra plain",
            "all of these"
        ],
        correct : "all of these"
    },
    {
        question : "In Koeppen classification, which is cool summer temperature?",
        option : [
            "c",
            "d",
            "F",
            "T"
        ],
        correct : "c"
    },
    {
        question : "In Koeppen classification, which is cool summer temperature?",
        option : [
            "A",
            "E",
            "C",
            "B"
        ],
        correct : "C"
    },
    {
        question : "In Koeppen classification, which is extremely continental temperatue?",
        option : [
            "c",
            "d",
            "F",
            "T"
        ],
        correct : "d"
    },
    {
        question : "In soil profile, C refers to",
        option : [
            "organic surface layer",
            "topsoil layer",
            "subsoil layer",
            "substratum layer"
        ],
        correct : "substratum layer"
    },
    {
        question : "Bangar is a type of",
        option : [
            "black cotton soil",
            "alluvial soil",
            "saline soil",
            "red and yellow soil"
        ],
        correct : "alluvial soil"
    },
    {
        question : "mechanical action of ocean waves is an example of",
        option : [
            "chemical weathering",
            "physical weathering",
            "biological weathering",
            "none of these"
        ],
        correct : "physical weathering"
    },
    {
        question : "khadar is a type of",
        option : [
            "black cotton soil",
            "alluvial soil",
            "saline soil",
            "red and yellow soil"
        ],
        correct : "alluvial soil"
    },
    {
        question : "regur is a term for",
        option : [
            "black cotton soil",
            "alluvial soil",
            "saline soil",
            "red and yellow soil"
        ],
        correct : "black cotton soil"
    },
    {
        question : "soil formation is dependent upon",
        option : [
            "vegetation",
            "time",
            "climate",
            "all of these"
        ],
        correct : "all of these"
    },
    {
        question : "self ploughing character is seen in",
        option : [
            "black cotton soil",
            "alluvial soil",
            "saline soil",
            "red and yellow soil"
        ],
        correct : "black cotton soil"
    },
    {
        question : "which of these is not a characteristics of pioneer species",
        option : [
            "ability to grow on bare rocks",
            "ability to tolerate extreme temperatures",
            "large size",
            "short life span"
        ],
        correct : "large size"
    },
    {
        question : "the term laterite soil is derived from latin later which means",
        option : [
            "red",
            "brick",
            "fertile",
            "infertile"
        ],
        correct : "brick"
    },
    {
        question : "\"the diversity that exists among different geographies\" is",
        option : [
            "alpha biodiversity",
            "beta biodiversity",
            "gamma biodiversity",
            "delta biodiversity"
        ],
        correct : "gamma biodiversity"
    },
    {
        question : "the elephant has a home range of several square kilometres, regulates the ecosystem by its habit of destructive feeding, and people can relate to this animal which is important for conservation. Given this background the elephant can be called as",
        option : [
            "umbrella species",
            "keystone species",
            "flagship species",
            "all of the above"
        ],
        correct : "all of the above"
    },
    {
        question : "\"the cost of impacts caused by emission of carbon dioxide\" is known as",
        option : [
            "cost of carbon",
            "economic cost of carbon",
            "social cost of carbon",
            "cultural cost of carbon"
        ],
        correct : "social cost of carbon"
    },
    {
        question : "soil formation is an example of",
        option : [
            "provisioning service",
            "regulating service",
            "supporting service",
            "cultural service"
        ],
        correct : "supporting service"
    },
    {
        question : "we prefer those areas for the creation of a conservation reserve where the level of threat is",
        option : [
            "very high",
            "medium",
            "very low",
            "non- existent"
        ],
        correct : "medium"
    },
    {
        question : "people come to sessa orchid sanctuary in arunachal pradesh to witness orchids, which in this context would be classified as",
        option : [
            "umbrella species",
            "keystone species",
            "flagship species",
            "extinct species"
        ],
        correct : "flagship species"
    },
    {
        question : "nutrient cycling is an example of",
        option : [
            "provisioning service",
            "regulating service",
            "supporting service",
            "cultural service"
        ],
        correct : "supporting service"
    },
    {
        question : "which of these is a stochastic factor?",
        option : [
            "birth rate",
            "death rate",
            "population structure",
            "environmental fluctuation"
        ],
        correct : "environmental fluctuation"
    },
    {
        question : "the \"subset of physical and biotic environmental factors that permit an animal (or plant) to survive and reproduce\" is the definition of",
        option : [
            "habitat",
            "ecosystem",
            "biome",
            "biosphere"
        ],
        correct : "habitat"
    },
    {
        question : "supply of medicines is an example of",
        option : [
            "provisioning service",
            "regulating service",
            "supporting service",
            "cultural service"
        ],
        correct : "provisioning service"
    },
    {
        question : "the fig tree bears fruits in times when animals do not have much access to food. In this context it would be a good example of",
        option : [
            "least concern species",
            "keystone species",
            "flagship species",
            "extinct species"
        ],
        correct : "keystone species"
    },
    {
        question : "according to Malthusain model",
        option : [
            "population grows in geometric progression, food supple increases in arithmetic progression",
            "population grows in geometric progression, food supply increases in geometric progression",
            "population grows in arithmetic progression, food supply increases in arithmetic progression",
            "population grows in arithmetic progression, food supply increases in geometric progression"
        ],
        correct : "population grows in geometric progression, food supple increases in arithmetic progression"
    },
    {
        question : "the logistic growth equation curve is",
        option : [
            "I shaped",
            "J shaped",
            "S shaped",
            "U shaped"
        ],
        correct : "S shaped"
    },
    {
        question : "which of these is not a pillar of sustainability?",
        option : [
            "environmental sustainability",
            "economic sustainability",
            "trans- boundary sustainability",
            "social sustainability"
        ],
        correct : "trans- boundary sustainability"
    },
    {
        question : "which of these is commonly observed during humanising of nature?",
        option : [
            "environmental determinism",
            "possibilism",
            "neodeterminism",
            "stop and go determinism"
        ],
        correct : "possibilism"
    },
    {
        question : "which of these is not observed in primitive societies?",
        option : [
            "environmental determinism",
            "possibilism",
            "neodeterminism",
            "stop and go determinism"
        ],
        correct : "stop and go determinism"
    },
    {
        question : "which of these is a preventive check according to Malthus?",
        option : [
            "foresight",
            "vice",
            "misery",
            "food"
        ],
        correct : "foresight"
    },
    {
        question : "which of these is a positive check according to Malthus?",
        option : [
            "late marriage",
            "war",
            "celibacy",
            "moral restraint"
        ],
        correct : "war"
    },
    {
        question : "which of these is a pillar of sustainability?",
        option : [
            "social sustainability",
            "industrial sustainability",
            "agricultural sustainability",
            "trans- boundary sustainability"
        ],
        correct : "social sustainability"
    },
    {
        question : "the demographic transition sees a society move from",
        option : [
            "high birth rate, low death rate to low birth rate, high death rate",
            "low birth rate, high death rate to low birth rate, low death rate",
            "high birth rate, high death rate to low birth rate, low death rate",
            "high birth rate, high death rate to low birth rate, high death rate"
        ],
        correct : "high birth rate, high death rate to low birth rate, low death rate"
    },
    {
        question : "the book \"An essay on the principle of population\" was written by",
        option : [
            "Darwin",
            "Malthus",
            "Spencer",
            "Owens"
        ],
        correct : "Malthus"
    },
    {
        question : "\"those resources that have been surveyed but we lack the technology to use them\" is a definition of",
        option : [
            "potential resources",
            "actual resources",
            "reserve resources",
            "stock resources"
        ],
        correct : "stock resources"
    },
    {
        question : "rain gardens are primarily meant to",
        option : [
            "reduce water usage",
            "increase recharge to groundwater",
            "protect existing water sources",
            "increase water flow to streams"
        ],
        correct : "increase recharge to groundwater"
    },
    {
        question : "timber from forests that s being harvested can be categorised under",
        option : [
            "potential resources",
            "actual resources",
            "reserve resources",
            "stock resources"
        ],
        correct : "actual resources"
    },
    {
        question : "which of these is the largest source of sulphur oxides in the atmosphere",
        option : [
            "electricity generation",
            "mobile sources",
            "industrial processes",
            "residential fuel"
        ],
        correct : "electricity generation"
    },
    {
        question : "which of these is the largest source of ammonia in the atmosphere",
        option : [
            "animal manicure",
            "mineral fertiliser",
            "crops and their decomposition",
            "human waste"
        ],
        correct : "animal manicure"
    },
    {
        question : "\"those resources that are currently being used after surveying, quantification and qualification\" is a definition of",
        option : [
            "potential resources",
            "actual resources",
            "reserve resources",
            "stock resources"
        ],
        correct : "actual resources"
    },
    {
        question : "hydrogen for nuclear fusion comes under the category of",
        option : [
            "potential resources",
            "actual resources",
            "reserve resources",
            "stock resources"
        ],
        correct : "stock resources"
    },
    {
        question : "low concentration ores comes in the category of",
        option : [
            "potential resources",
            "actual resources",
            "reserve resources",
            "stock resources"
        ],
        correct : "reserve resources"
    },
    {
        question : "\"those resources that may be used in future\" is a definition of",
        option : [
            "potential resources",
            "actual resources",
            "reserve resources",
            "stock resources"
        ],
        correct : "potential resources"
    },
    {
        question : "oil that has not been drilled can be categorised under",
        option : [
            "potential resources",
            "actual resources",
            "reserve resources",
            "stock resources"
        ],
        correct : "potential resources"
    },
    {
        question : "Singrauli can be best categorised as",
        option : [
            "mining town",
            "garrison town",
            "educational town",
            "religious town"
        ],
        correct : "mining town"
    },
    {
        question : "rain gardens are primarily meant to",
        option : [
            "reduce water usage",
            "increase recharge to groundwater",
            "protect existing water sources",
            "increase water flow to streams"
        ],
        correct : "increase recharge to groundwater"
    },
    {
        question : "which of these is/ are example(s) of mitigation measures to mitigate impacts of linear infrastructure on wildlife?",
        option : [
            "land bridges",
            "canopy bridges",
            "glider poles",
            "all of these"
        ],
        correct : "all of these"
    },
    {
        question : "Varanasi can be best categorised as",
        option : [
            "mining town",
            "garrison town",
            "educational town",
            "religious town"
        ],
        correct : "religious town"
    },
    {
        question : "'the ability to produce a good using fewer inputs than another place' is",
        option : [
            "comparative advantage",
            "absolute advantage",
            "production advantage",
            "resource advantage"
        ],
        correct : "absolute advantage"
    },
    {
        question : "which of these is a factor governing barrier effect of roads?",
        option : [
            "presence and location of animal crossings",
            "movement pattern of species",
            "species specific preference of road use",
            "all of these"
        ],
        correct : "all of these"
    },
    {
        question : "Visakhapatnam can be best categorised as",
        option : [
            "administrative town",
            "industrial town",
            "transport town",
            "commercial town"
        ],
        correct : "transport town"
    },
    {
        question : "which of these is a factor governing barrier effect of roads?",
        option : [
            "traffic intensity",
            "speed of vehicles",
            "driver sensitivity",
            "all of these"
        ],
        correct : "all of these"
    },
    {
        question : "which of these is/ are example(s) of mitigation measures to mitigate impacts of linear infrastructure on wildlife?",
        option : [
            "bridge underpass",
            "box culverts",
            "pipe culverts",
            "all of these"
        ],
        correct : "all of these"
    },
    {
        question : "Bhilai can be best categorised as ",
        option : [
            "administrative town",
            "industrial town",
            "transport town",
            "commercial town"
        ],
        correct : "industrial town"
    },
    {
        question : "which of these is not a use value?",
        option : [
            "direct value",
            "indirect value",
            "option value",
            "existence value"
        ],
        correct : "existence value"
    },
    {
        question : "'the conditions determined by physical, social, economic and environmental factors or processes which increase the susceptibility of an individual, a community, assets or systems to the impact of hazards.' is a definition for",
        option : [
            "hazard",
            "exposure",
            "vulnerability",
            "disaster"
        ],
        correct : "vulnerability"
    },
    {
        question : "'a process, phenomenon or human activity that may cause loss of life, injury or other health impacts, property damage, social and economic disruption or environmental degradation.' is a definition for ",
        option : [
            "hazard",
            "exposure",
            "vulnerability",
            "disaster"
        ],
        correct : "hazard"
    },
    {
        question : "which of these uses imputed willingness to pay?",
        option : [
            "market price method",
            "replacement cost method",
            "travel cost method",
            "contingent valuation method"
        ],
        correct : "replacement cost method"
    },
    {
        question : "'a serious disruption of the functioning of a community or a society at any scale due to hazardous events interacting with conditions of exposure, vulnerability and capacity, leading to one or more of the following: human, material, economic and environmental losses and impacts' is a definition for",
        option : [
            "hazard",
            "exposure",
            "vulnerability",
            "disaster"
        ],
        correct : "disaster"
    },
    {
        question : "which if these is not a non- use value?",
        option : [
            "direct value",
            "existence value",
            "altruistic value",
            "bequest value"
        ],
        correct : "direct value"
    },
    {
        question : "Bathymetric LiDAR uses",
        option : [
            "far infrared light",
            "near infrared light",
            "orange light",
            "green light"
        ],
        correct : "green light"
    },
    {
        question : "\"the combination of all strengths , attributes and resources available within an organisation community or society to manage and reduce disaster risks and strengthen resilience.\" is a definition for ",
        option : [
            "contingency",
            "disaster management",
            "vulnerability",
            "capacity"
        ],
        correct : "capacity"
    },
    {
        question : "the value of leaving use and non- use values for offspring's or future generations is called",
        option : [
            "altruistic value",
            "bequest value",
            "existence value",
            "option value"
        ],
        correct : "bequest value"
    },
    {
        question : "the frequency of flyover is an indicator of",
        option : [
            "spatial resolution",
            "temporal resolution",
            "spectral resolution",
            "radiometric resolution"
        ],
        correct : "temporal resolution"
    },
]